nyit.edu 2018-12-30

# Privacy Statement | Policies | NYIT

By using our website or web services, you consent to the collection and use of your information by New York Institute of Technology (“NYIT”). NYIT collects personal information to make our site(s) and service(s) more relevant and rewarding for you to use.

For each visitor to our web pages, our web server automatically recognizes your domain, service provider, operating system, and Internet browser. Our Web server additionally records usage of pages by our visitors. We use this information, in aggregate, for research reports and performance surveys. We sometimes use this non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our site and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience.

Some of NYIT's site(s) and service(s) collect personally identifiable information to further personalize your experience within a site. Some site(s) and service(s) require that you provide personally identifiable information in order to participate in the activities and offerings within.

We may use the information you provide about yourself to fulfill your requests for our products, programs, and services, to respond to your inquiries about our offerings, and to offer you other products, programs or services that we believe may be of interest to you. We sometimes use this information to communicate with you, such as to notify you when we make changes to our services, to fulfill a request by you, or to contact you about your account with us. Most of our communications provide an “opt-out” feature.

We may also use your information to update internal systems. This allows for seamless delivery of services and resources to you across NYIT’s systems.

NYIT’s websites(s) and service(s) may contain email services, bulletin board services, chat areas, news groups, forums, communities, personal Web pages, calendars, photo displays, and/or other message or communication facilities designed to enable you to communicate with others (collectively, “Communication Services”). The information we collect in connection with these Communication Services is used to provide an interactive experience. We use this information to facilitate participation in these Communication Services. Within many of these Communication Services, NYIT provides you multiple privacy options that allow you to restrict the use and viewability of your information to others.

## Third Party Disclosure

NYIT does not sell, rent, give away, or loan any identifiable information to any third party other than agents and contractors of NYIT.

Agents and contractors of NYIT who have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this privacy statement by, for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for NYIT.

NYIT may release personal information when we believe, in good faith, that such release is reasonably necessary to (i.) comply with law, (ii.) enforce or apply the terms of any of our user agreements, or (iii.) protect the rights, property, or safety of NYIT, our users, or others.

Some of our site(s) and service(s) contain links to other sites whose information practices may be different than ours. Visitors should consult the other sites' privacy statements as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties. 

## Pixels, Web Beacons and Cookies

NYIT utilizes “cookies” to enhance the experience on our website and for marketing purposes. Cookies are text files we place in the browsers of your computer, mobile device, tablet or other device to store your preferences. We use cookies to understand website usage and to improve the content and offerings on our Site. We also may use cookies to offer you products, programs, or services, or to provide you with personalized online display advertising tailored to your interests. In addition, we may use the services of third parties to collect and use anonymous information about your visits to and interactions with our website through the use of technologies such as cookies to personalize advertisements.

You may refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. Your browser may also be set not to accept cookies.

To delete or manage cookies settings, please follow the instructions for your web browser:

NYIT may collect a limited set of personally identifiable information about you to help manage our online advertising and promotions. To collect this information, we or our third party advertising providers use, “web beacons” (also known as “clear gifs” and “pixel tags”), in conjunction with cookies. For more information about the use of these technologies by us and our third-party advertising service providers, including how to opt out of these technologies, please visit the [Consumer Opt Out page on Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/).

Our website utilizes [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/), [Matamo Analytics](https://matomo.org/) (formerly Piwik), Facebook pixels, and other software that may track and collect information from your device from the time you access our website. The information automatically collected is subject to their respective privacy policies. Please read more about [Google Analytics’ privacy policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/), [Matamo Analytics’ privacy policy](https://matomo.org/privacy/), and [Facebook’s privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) for information on how these companies use your information. Information collected may include:

  * Internet domain and Internet address of the computer, mobile device or other device you use to access the Site.
  * Essential technical information collected includes the identification of the page or service you are requesting, type of browser and operating system you are using; and the date and time of access.
  * Optional information is collected only if you choose to send it. For example, choosing to complete an online form, register for an event, or send an email are optional actions. 

NYIT may use remarketing pixels created by Google, LinkedIn, Facebook, or other services to show you advertisements or relevant content on these channels or across the Internet. You may manually opt out of these services or the vendor’s use of cookies by visiting their websites. Here are ways to opt out of third-party services that may or may not be utilized on this website:

  * [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/) or [this second link](https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/)

## Social Media Features

Our Site includes social media buttons and widgets, developed and maintained by NYIT-approved vendors and/or third-party services “Social Media Functions.” These features may collect your IP address and pages you visited, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Functions are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Sites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy or statement of the company providing it.

## Updates to This Privacy Statement

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this privacy statement at any time. Please review this privacy statement periodically for changes. If you have questions regarding this statement, please contact the Privacy Officer, New York Institute of Technology, Tower House, Room B15, Old Westbury, NY 11568 or [privacy@nyit.edu](mailto:privacy@nyit.edu).

## Contacting the Website

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this website or your dealings with this website, please contact NYIT’s webmaster via the contact form.

This Privacy Statement was last updated on February 27, 2018.
